Brandon Franklin

Loxahatchee, Florida - 561.674.6225 - brandon.h.franklin@gmail.com

Objective:

Curate robust web applications utilizing the latest technologies and adhering to the highest of standards. Experienced with stages of web development including design concept and prototyping, QA, deployment, release and maintenance. Strong background in design theory and effectively communicating between all teams involved in the software development lifecycle.

Education:

Graduated 2011: Bachelors of Graphic Design, Digital Media Arts College, Boca Raton, FL

- Delta Epsilon Iota Honor Society

Work Experience:

7Summits, an IBM Company

Senior Front End Developer, October 2021 - Present

- Assist with the training and onboarding of new team members
- Mentor new team members on projects so they feel empowered when working alone on future projects
- Work with tech leads to define user story solution notes, estimations, acceptance criteria, documentation and deployments
- Participate in quarterly projects with team members to improve development standards and define best practices for other engineers and members of the technology team

Front End Developer, November 2019 - October 2021

- Utilize Salesforce and modern web development technologies to create solutions for our clients
- Build Aura/Lightning Web Components for Salesforce Lightning Experience and Communities
- Contribute to Product IP, including bolts and accelerators available in Salesforce AppExchange
- Work with team to write, test and troubleshoot Apex controllers/triggers
- Responsive design utilizing the Salesforce Lightning Design System
- Configuring Communities within the Lightning Community Builder
- Interfacing directly with clients in coordination with the project's Tech Lead
- Utilizing Jira software to work on projects using Agile methodology for project management
- Working with back-end developers to create solutions in tandem

Cendyn

Lead Front End Developer, January 2019 - November 2019

- Conceptualize, prototype and build product features that integrate with legacy and modern technologies
- Work with other team leaders to determine tech stacks for product development (Vue, .NET Core, SQL)
- Update and maintain product integrity through ongoing enhancements
- Conduct code reviews for internal and offshore teams
- Create and update documentation for best practices, component usage and API consumption using the latest features in JavaScript

Front End Developer, February 2016 - January 2019

- Collaborate with both UX Designers and Back End Developers
- Prototype and rapidly iterate to test assumptions for product features
- Aid QA team in exploratory testing and business related defects
- Create, implement and maintain living UI kit

Brandon Franklin

Loxahatchee, Florida - 561.674.6225 - brandon.h.franklin@gmail.com

Production Manager, May 2015 - February 2016

- Implement, train and maintain industry best practices for CSS and HTML
- Monitored the status of each project and worked to ensure goals were met by the production team
- Proactively identified potential production challenges and provided solutions to prevent in the future
- Ensured proper communication between internal departments, Managers, and Customers
- Organized alerts and scheduled jobs for server maintenance, data processing, and deployments

Product Services Manager, July 2013 – May 2015

Production Coordinator, July 2012 - July 2013

Web Production Specialist, July 2011 - July 2012

Projects:

Sales Suite Product Redesign

- Responsible for leading a team of other departments through the ideation, iteration, validation, prototyping and testing of concepts for the redesign of our flagship product.
- Directly influence tech stack and product design decisions for a maintainable and scalable environment.

Living UI Kit

- Worked with the UX Design team to cultivate a philosophy for rebranding the entire suite of 22 products. This involved conceptualization and prototyping items to include in the kit.
 - o Implementation & Testing
 - o "How to" tutorial
 - Updates and maintenance of code base

Hilton Worldwide Product Suite

Responsible for the recruitment, training, and development of 4 new team members in an effort to
increase productivity by the end of the year. The team was able to exceed expectations two-fold and
deliver the final release of the project early and under budget.

Skills:

Proficiencies

HTML5, CSS3, LESS/SASS Preprocessing, Bootstrap, Foundation, JavaScript, ES6, Material UI, Tailwind, Bulma, Vue, Vuex, jQuery, Version Control (TFS, GIT, SVN), Salesforce Administration and Development, Salesforce Experience Cloud, Lightning Web Components, Responsive Web Design, Cross-Browser Compatibility, Adobe Creative Suite, Windows/MAC, VS Code, IntelliJ, Working with Offshore/Remote Teams

Familiarizations

Angular 1x, React, Nuxt, TypeScript, MVC, ASP.NET, .NET Core, API Creation, Node, NPM, Yarn, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Browserify, Lean UX, Asynchronous Programming, Unit Testing, DevOps, AutoRabit

Certifications

Salesforce Certified Javascript Developer, Salesforce Certified Administrator, Salesforce Certified UX Designer

Define. Measure. Analyze. Implement. Control.